hello and welcome to the seventh
tutorial on how to program in gript 2 so
let's open our NPC in the level editor
and make it say yellow is equal
to
stuff what we're doing is instead of
making yellow equal to a number we're
making it equal to the text
stuff now we can make if player. chat is
equal to
Yellow then this. chat is equal
to you said yellow I mean
stuff capital S also I want to change it
from on created to on player
chats so what it's doing it's making
yellow equal to the string value of
stuff or just stuff and we're checking
to see if your your chat is equal to
Yellow which is stuff so if you say
stuff with capital S then everything in
here will
happen hi nothing
happens
stuff nothing
happens oh there's no semicolon there I
feel stupid now yeah you got to try to
watch out for that you said stuff now
you can also just change this to change
here
to stuff if you wanted to but for the
sake of tutorial I made yellow now let's
make yellow equal to
two it will say yellow but let's say I
want to say three I can either make it
say three or for the sake of the
tutorial make yellow
increase by one there's two ways to do
that yellow equals yellow + 1 this takes
this overrides yellow it it sort of it
sort of deletes the old yellow and
creates a new
yellow yellow's equal to the old yellow
plus one so the old yellow is two as you
can see
here and it's 2 + 1 so yellow will be
three now
watch
I'm going to say high it'll say
three I can also
do plus plus as simple as that and it'll
automatically increase by one by
itself
high now let's you can also do minus
minus to make it decrease by one you can
also now let's make a new variable
purple is equal to
five let's make yellow equal to yellow
plus
purple and change this to created
oncreated so yellow is equal to Yellow
which is 2 plus purple which is five so
it should say
seven just say seven we can also make it
multiply by doing a little
star so it's 10 now we can divide
it
0.4 we can also uh there's there's a lot
of things we could do we could do to the
power of we
could yeah there's just a
lot and so I think that concludes this
tutorial we learned a bit more about
variables how they can equal letters we
learned how we could manipulate them and
change them around so yeah that's it for
this tutorial and bye